Guide to the Carole Hyatt Papers 1947-2006 (bulk, 1980s-1990s) MS 3105
New-York Historical Society
- Series II. Research and Working Files, 1976-2005; 6.5 Linear feet
  - Subseries II.A. Interview Transcripts and Notes, 1985-2002; 3.6 Linear feet
    - Women and Earnings Power (?) Interviewees (4 folders), 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 14-17)
      8 files, found loose but appear to relate to the topic of the impact on women of having earnings power. Names: Jaclyn(?) Kennedy (with 1 tape), Nan Bernstein, Elly Guggenheim (with 1 tape), Faabian Gershon (with 2 tapes), Judy Rosener, Swanee(?) Hunt (with 1 tape), Joan Sandler (with 1 tape), Arlynn Zimmerman
    - Unidentified topics, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      2 files, each with notes and 1 tape: Jim Dale, Erika Freeman, Patty Rose
    - Unidentified topics (3 folders), undated (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
      Interviewees: Lang Rust, Regina Montoya, Mary Lynne Heldmann, Russell Harrison (with 1 tape, that also includes Lewis Hollwegg), Theodore Scudder Jr. (with 1 tape), Brooke Mahoney (with 2 tapes), Roxane Mankin (with 1 tape), Eryn Cunningham (with 1 tape)
  - Subseries II.B. Working Files, 1976-2005; 2.9 Linear feet
    The subseries includes Carole Hyatt's files concerning her various initiatives, both proposed and realized. The subseries includes the proposals for at least two of Hyatt's published books ("When Smart People Fail" and "Lifetime Employability"), along with book projects that did not come to fruition. There are interview logs and interview release forms and a few interview notes mixed into the files, but generally the interview transcripts and notes are found in subseries II.A.
    Beyond Hyatt's books, the subseries holds files with Hyatt's remarks for workshops, panels, and the like; proposed partnerships with corporations and with other consultants; various notes and reference material informing her work; and two of Hyatt's reports from the mid-1970s during her years at her firm, Child Research Service. There is a rich set of files on her Japan-based initiatives, circa 1990, that she executed with Noriko Sakayori. And a set of files with proposals for television shows and segments, especially for a situation comedy (sitcom) to be named "Shirley."
    Because the content varies considerably among the topics represented in the subseries,the container list provides more detail on content, including identifying where a few interview notes can be found.
    The subseries is arranged by topic. The subseries opens with Hyatt's early Child Research Service reports and moves into files pertaining to her various book projects, advancing in rough chronological order. Following these book-oriented files are those concerning workshops and other initiatives, concluding with files of miscellaneous notes and reference material.
    - Child Research Service, Inc. Seminar on Children's Advertising, Presented to National Oats Co., 1976 October (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Child Research Service, Inc. Seminar on Children, Presented to ABC Television, 1979 November (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - McCollum/Spielman Associates, Inc./Child Research Service. Seminar on Marketing to Children and Their Parents, Presented to The Alberto-Culver Company, 1983 September (Box 7, Folder 6)
      Document marked up for re-use with another client.
    - When Smart People Fail (3 folders), 1985-1992 (Box 7, Folder 7-9)
      Includes, among other documents, book proposal (1985) from Hyatt and Linda Gottlieb for "When Smart People Fail: How Defeat Can Lead to Success"; publication contract with Simon & Schuster (1985); contract with the book's German publisher (1987); examples of interview request letters; interview logs; interviewee releases; permissions for quotations from published works; summary of editorial comments from Patricia Soliman at Simon & Schuster; a letter from China observing the relevance of the book to that country at that time (1988?) and offering to write a Chinese translation. Two transcripts with the logs: Bert Salzman and Richard Melluzzo.
    - Winning Combinations. Proposals, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      Proposals for a book "Winning Combinations: Having a Nontraditional Relationship that Works" and collaboration agreement between Hyatt and Constance deSwaan.
    - Winning Combinations. Miscellaneous Notes, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Winning Combinations. Releases, Notes, etc., 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Winning Combinations. Research Material (3 folders), 1980s (Box 7, Folder 13-15)
      Holds clippings, articles, tearsheets, statistics and other published reference material.
    - Shifting Gears (3 folders), 1990-1992 (Box 7, Folder 16-18)
      Includes, among other documents, brochure/marketing suggestions for a Shifting Gears (SG) workshop titled "Partnering for Productivity Within the Lean Organization," example contracts for related seminars by Hyatt; Canadian media interview schedule for book; notes for "combination speech for Smart People and Shifting Gears"; file of reference material and notes labeled as "not used" for a one day SG seminar (March 24, 1990).
    - Selling Game (2 folders), 1984-1993 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
      Includes, among other documents, outline of talks at: National Association of Professional Sales Women (1982), Transart Industries (1984), Citicorp (1985), National Association of Bank Women (1986), women's groups in Westchester (1990) and New Mexico (1993), and speech "Reinventing Yourself for Success" via NAFE satellite (1993)
    - Lifelong Employability, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      Includes book proposal by Hyatt and Stephen M. Silverman "Carole Hyatt's Eight-Hour Career Makeover: How to Guarantee Yourself Lifelong Employability"
    - Corporate Survivors, 1991-1994 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Includes chapter outline for proposed book "Corporate Survivors: Life After the Shakedown," interview logs, notes from an interview(?) with Judith Brodwick, and some other notes.
    - When Smart People Become Wise (4 folders), circa 1992-1994 (Box 8, Folder 5-8)
      Includes, among other documents, interviewee releases and logs; proposals, concepts, outlines, brief introduction for book "When Smart People Become Wise: A New Psychology of Life Choices" (or alternative sub-title: The Art of Problem Finding); draft questionnaires; letters from potential assistants; reference material; and notes. The file has a copy of the "When Smart People Fail" proposal that includes the first page (missing in an earlier file's copy).
    - Handling Success, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      Holds a small number of notes (possibly from interviews) and reference material.
    - Money Book / Dual Incomes (4 folders), circa 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 10-13)
      Includes, among other documents, proposal for book "Breaking the Money Barrier: When Women [Outearn (struckthrough)] Have More Money Men"; notes; 1 cassette tape of Mary Pebley; 1 cassette tape interview with Nina McLemore; some transcripts (Sandy Guffman); reference material.
    - Job Game Over 40 / Retirement, circa 1998 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      Includes three files with, among other documents, a proposal for book "The Job Game After 40", a proposal for a book engaging with retirement, and a proposal for American Express for a workshop "Shifting Gears for the 401k Retiree Market"
    - Workshops, etc. United States (8 folders), 1987-2001 (Box 8, Folder 15-22)
      Includes outlines of remarks and other documents related to Hyatt's presentations to women's groups, corporate sessions, and others on risktaking, backlash against women, ideation/creativity, leadership, etc., especially as these relate to women, though not necessarily so. One extensive file is "Women and Risk Taking: Expanding Your Comfort Level" presented to Digital Equipment Corp's Women's Conclave (1992); intermixed in that file are documents related to Hyatt's presentation "The New 'Work Family' for Survival in the Year 2000" at the 1992 Woman Inc trade fair in Jamaica.
    - Japan Initiatives (4 folders), 1988-1992 (Box 9, Folder 1-4)
      Includes Hyatt's extensive correspondence with Noriko Sakayori in Japan and other documents concerning their collaboration on seminars, speeches, and other Hyatt initiatives and business proposals in Japan. Topics primarily included a "woman's natural ability for business" and mentoring/networking.
    - International Workshops other than Japan, 1984, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Files on a United Nations Women Managers Assertiveness Training in Vienna (1984) and on women's focus group in Eastern Europe (Budapest and Poland).
    - International Travel. Asia other than Japan, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      A small file on Vietnam and a file summarizing the International Women's Forum's delegation (including Hyatt) visit to China and Hong Kong.
    - Proposals and Alliances (3 folders), 1990-2001 (Box 9, Folder 7-9)
      Includes various files on possible and actual partnerships with organizations and initiatives. Among these is a creative workshop, named ThoughtStorm, in a collaboration with consultant Ruth Zanes and the cartoonist Mort Gerberg, and a series of Head of State documentaries aimed at the tourism industry.
    - Television Show Proposals (4 folders), 1990-1996 (Box 9, Folder 10-13)
      Includes extensive files on a proposed sitcom "Shirley," with the feature character a woman starting a new life after the death of her husband. Also files on a quiz show "The Family Game," "Chances Are" short segments for Mary Tyler Moore's show "Today's Woman," "Focus Group" for daytime TV, and others.
    - Miscellaneous Notes (3 folders), 1988-2001 (Box 9, Folder 14-16)
    - Miscellaneous Reference Material (2 folders), 1990s-2005 (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
    - Books (2), 1982, 1990 (Box 9)
      "Unnecessary Choices: The Hidden Life of the Executive Woman" by Edith Gilson with Susan Kane, inscribed by Gilson; and "Singles: The New Americans" by Jacqueline Simenauer.
    - Miscellaneous Letters, Mailing Lists, Business Cards, 1990s (Box 9, Folder 19)
      Among other documents, includes a "Kolbe Talent Analysis" result for Hyatt.
    - Miscellaneous Lists and Notes about Tapes, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
      Includes lists of some of the Hyatt tapes. These lists provide some context for some of the audiotapes in Series III, and were used by the processing archivist as a source for some of the notes in the Series III description.
- Series III. Audiotapes, 1975-2003, undated; 8 Linear feet
  This series includes approximately 670 audiocassette tapes, 457 of which have been digitized for access. None of the tapes were listened to during processing but the overall subject content is clear from the tape labels and overall collection context. The bulk of the tapes are of interviews that Carole Hyatt conducted in the 1980s and 1990s during her research for her books, both those realized and those contemplated but not realized or realized in a different form than originally planned. Most of these interviews were with individuals, but also included focus groups of men and/or women, couples, business partners, or other combinations. The bulk, reflecting the experiences of regular people, are with relatively unknown individuals, but some notable figures appear, such as newscaster Walter Cronkite, author William Shirer, boxer Gerry Cooney, former U.S. senator George McGovern, Vice-Presidential candidate Geraldine Ferraro, entrepreneur and founder of Famous Amos cookies Wally Amos, Apple co-founder Steve Wozniak, and New York University president and former Congressman John Brademas.
  Generally, the tapes are well-labeled as to the name of the interviewee, but often lack a date or identification as to which project they pertain to. Indexes found in Series II (folder title "Miscellaneous Lists and Notes about Tapes," Box 9, folder 20) can provide guidance as to the context of some of the tapes and were used by the processing archivist in developing notes in the container list.
  The tapes also include recordings of Hyatt appearances on radio and television talk shows, remarks at presentations and conferences, and, judging from the labels, her dictation of book outlines and chapters (possibly "Shifting Gears" specifically). Other tapes include recordings made by Hyatt of talks given by others on topics of interest, as well as commercially produced tapes on time management, motivational techniques, and other topics of use to Hyatt in her research.
  In 2016, 457 of the audiotapes were digitized for accessibility and use. These were chosen more or less randomly so there is no overall difference between the content of the digitized and non-digitized tapes. Different access restrictions apply to both and are further described at the subseries level.
  Subseries III.A. Audiotapes, Digitized
  Subseries III.B. Audiotapes, Not Digitized
  Access restrictions apply to both subseries and these are further described at the subseries level.
  - Subseries III.A. Audiotapes, Digitized, 1975-2003, undated; 6 Linear feet (457 cassette tapes in 6 boxes; 1.09 terabytes of digital files)
    This subseries includes 457 audiotapes in the collection that have been digitized and are available to be listened to on-site at New-York Historical Society. In digital form, these amounted to 914 digital files totaling 1.09 terabytes. The container list identifies all digitized audiotapes, with information taken from the labels on the tapes (that is, no tapes were listened to to determine content).
    The title used in the container list is the interviewee name or other core identifying information as found on the tape label and as used to name the related digital files. Generally each tape includes only one interviewee but where multiple names appear, those are included also in the title. Variant forms and spellings of names were common, both from side to side of a tape and among multiple tapes used for an interviewee. Variants were also found between the tapes and related paper documents in the collection. The processing archivist noted some of these variant names, especially where it seemed they might impede discovery. But surely not all variants were noted, nor was any attempt made to reconcile them or determine a single "correct" name to use. Accordingly, users should keep in mind the potential for name variants and be cautious in relying exclusively on keyword searches.
    Because it is expected that patrons will only have access to the digital files, not to the physical tapes themselves, all additional information found on the label was transcribed into a note at the file level; these transcriptions are identified in the note within "quotation marks." Information not in quotation marks was supplied by the archivist in an effort to help patrons navigate the material, especially in terms of relating the digital files they will be using to the original tape.
    All the tapes are represented in digital form by two files, one for side A and one for side B. This is emphasized in the container list title with the reference to "1 tape/2 files." Some interviews required two or more tapes; when this was clearly identifiable during processing it was noted in the title by such references as "2 tapes/4 files." When the possible connection between tapes was uncertain, the potential connection is referred to in a note at the tape level.
    Both sides of all tapes were digitized without regard to, or even knowledge of, whether the second side had content. Accordingly, the second digital file associated with a tape may be, and likely often will be, blank. It is unknown if Hyatt did this consistently, but the labels on the tapes are commonly noted as to whether the second side (Side B) had content and to what extent (e.g., 1/8, full side, etc.). The use of multiple tapes is often indicated by labels referencing side 3, side 4, etc. The presence of such leading indicators was noted by the archivist in the container list. On the other hand, many tapes are labeled on one side only, with nothing noted on Side B. It seems likely that these were indicators that Side B was blank. However, the archivist did not want to imply this, as it might not be the case, and so no reference is made in the notes to the absence of a label on Side B.
    Very few of the tapes were labeled to indicate which book or project they related to. However, indexes in the paper files provide this information for some of the tapes. These indexes are found in Series II (folder title "Miscellaneous Lists and Notes about Tapes," Box 9, folder 20). These indexes were used as the source for some of the notes added to the container list by the processing archivist.
    Approximately one-half of the digitized tapes had dates on their labels. These tapes are presented first in the container list, in chronological order. These are followed by the other tapes, which are undated. Undated tapes are arranged in alphabetical order by interviewee surname, group name, or other key identifier from the label. Some undated tapes could be associated with a dated tape and so were included at that point in the container list.
    The physical audiotapes are arranged differently from the container list. These are boxed in the order in which they were digitized, with each tape assigned a sequence number. The sequence number/order of digitization was random with no relationship to chronology, subject matter, etc.
    The digital files are maintained by the Digital Collections staff. The file names include a combination of the sequence number, an "a" or "b" indicating the side of the tape, and the interviewee or other content identifier from the tape label. For content spanning two or more tapes, each with its unique sequence number, a "c," "d," etc. is used with the name to associate the files.
    Conditions Governing Access
    There are conditions governing access to the audiotapes and to the digital files of those tapes. For further information about these conditions, patrons must contact the manuscripts curator at manuscripts@nyhistory.org in advance of their visit.
    - Sell More -- Easier and Faster (1 tape/2 files), 1975 (Box T1, Item 020)
      Commercial product by Alan Cimberg. (Cimberg's name was used in naming the related digital files) [On index, re: motivation tapes]
    - Ophthalmology, Vol 14, No. 1 (1 tape/2 files), 1976 (Box T3, Item 192)
      Commercial product from the Audio-Digest Foundation. Additional label written on by Hyatt: "Richard Casey, Side 1" (Casey's name was used in naming the related digital files)
    - Everything You've Always Wanted to Know About Energy but Were Too Weak To Ask (1 tape/2 files), 1977 (Box T1, Item 019)
      Commercial product by Success Motivation Institute. Featuring speaker Naura Hayden. (Hayden's name was used in naming the related digital files.) Includes leaflet with Hayden's energy drink recipe and vitamin regimen. [On index, re: motivation tapes]
    - Adachi. Woman '79 (1 tape/2 files), 1979 (Box T1, Item 042)
      [On index, re: radio interviews]
    - Cush, Pat (1 tape/2 files), 1978 June 18 (Box T1, Item 025)
      [Per index, re: Selling Games]
    - Shaw, Brad (1 tape/2 files), 1979 May 3 (Box T1, Item 053)
      "Dayton, O. WAV1. Ends at 290." [On index, re: radio interviews]
    - Hyatt, Carole (1 tape/2 files), 1979 May 16 (Box T1, Item 014)
      Side A: "5/16-17/79 book tour. San Francisco TV/Dallas Radio" Side B: Cookbook session #1"
    - Hyatt, Carole (1 tape/2 files), 1980 March 5 (Box T1, Item 011)
      "WHK/WMMS" "Cleveland" ":18:30"
    - Hyatt, Carole and June Esserman with David Hartman (1 tape/2 files), 1980 September 22 (Box T1, Item 010)
      "Survey on Men's Attitudes" "Good Morning America"
    - O'Connor, Jenny (1 tape/2 files), 1982 June 4 (Box T1, Item 021)
      "The Nine." [On index, re: getting older]
    - The Inner Game: Self-Confidence (1 tape/2 files), 1984 (Box T1, Item 018)
      Commercial product by Windstar Foundation/Soundworks Inc. Features speaker Timothy Gallwey. (Gallwey's name was used in naming the related digital files) [On index, re: motivation tapes]
    - Fox, Muriel (1 tape/2 files), 1984 May (Box T2, Item 089)
      Labeled on both sides of tape. [On index, re: getting older]
    - Polykoff [or Polkoff], Shirley (1 tape/2 files), 1984 June 12 (Box T1, Item 065)
      See Polykoff, item 090, for likely second half. [On index, re: getting older]
    - Polykoff, Shirley (1 tape/2 files), 1984 June 12 (Box T2, Item 090)
      Side 1 is noted as side 3 and side 2 is noted as side 4. See Polykoff, item 060 for likely first half. [On index, re: getting older]
    - Champion, Marge (2 tapes/4 files), 1984 August (Box T3, Item 189-190)
      Labeled on three sides of the two tapes. [Per index, re: When Smart People Fail]
    - Barber, Stephanie (1 tape/2 files), 1984 August 4 (Box T1, Item 079)
      "Interview. Getting older." Side 2: "1/2 tape"
    - Fitzgibbon, Tom (2 tapes/4 files), 1984 December 31 (Box T3, Item 211-212)
      "40+" Labeled on all 4 sides of 2 tapes.
    - Steele, Jo; Bartlett, Dick (1 tape/2 files), 1985 January (Box T1, Item 023)
      Side A (1st file): "Jo Steele -- Dallas, TX -- 1/2 tape. Leaving Corporate to start own trans[?] design biz." [On index, re: getting older]. "Dick Bartlett--VP, Markting, Mary Kay." Side B (2nd file): "2nd half of Bartlett. Interview did not pick up -- blank side"
    - Terry, Ellen (1 tape/1 file), 1985 January 17 (Box T5, Item 350a)
      "Real estate. Dallas, Tx". One side only; see Karsh, Elaine (item 350b) for second side of tape. [Per index, re: When Smart People Fail]
    - Karsh, Elaine (1 tape/1 file), 1985 January 23 (Box T5, Item 350b)
      "Adv. Employment Ag, L.A." One side only; see Terry, Ellen (item 350a) for first side of tape. [Per index, re: When Smart People Fail]
    - Sincerely Yours (1 tape/2 files), 1985 January 23 (Box T1, Item 022)
      "Employment [Agents?] [Agreements?]" "L.A." [On index, re: getting older]
    - 40+ Club (1 tape/2 files), 1985 February (Box T2, Item 086)
      Side 1 label: "Ed Olsen, Pres." Side 2 label: "P.R. Director - Harold Mero(?); Education Dir - Lawrence close". [On index, re: getting older]
    - Smith, Ether (1 tape/2 files), 1985 May (Box T5, Item 335)
      "40+ Club. 43." "out of work, wife works." [Per index, re: When Smart People Fail]
    - Sandlin, Virginia (1 tape/2 files), 1985 May 8 (Box T4, Item 311)
      "failure." [Per index, re: When Smart People Fail]
    - Fitzgibbon, Maria (1 tape/2 files), 1985 May 16 (Box T3, Item 209)
      "Failure"
    - Lee, Makenzie [or MacKenzie] (2 tapes/4 files), 1985 May 16 (Box T6, Item 424-425)
      "failure." Labeled on three sides of two tapes, with third side noted as "1/3 tape." [Per index, re: When Smart People Fail]
    - Lee, Makenzie [or MacKenzie] (1 tape/2 files), undated (Box T6, Item 427)
      "Plan-how to"
    - Reinach, Jackie [or Renaik?] (1 tape/2 files), 1985 May 16 (Box T5, Item 323)
      Both sides labeled, with the second side noted as "1/3." [Per index, re: When Smart People Fail]
    - Cohen, Rob (1 tape/2 files), 1985 May 24 (Box T3, Item 188)
      Side 2: "1/8 tape" [Per index, re: When Smart People Fail]
    - Teitelbaum, David [or Tietlebaum?] (1 tape/2 files), 1985 May 25 (Box T5, Item 351)
      "failure." Labeled on both sides of tape, with second side noted as "1/8". [Per index, re: When Smart People Fail]
    - Lee, Makenzie [or MacKenzie] (1 tape/2 files), 1985 May 29 (Box T6, Item 426)
      Labeled on both sides of the tape.
    - Leff, Ilene (1 tape/2 files), 1985 May 29 (Box T6, Item 428)
      "Revlon. Personnel Dir." Labeled on both sides of the tape, with second side noting "1/3 side." [Per index, re: When Smart People Fail]
    - Baum, Robert (1 tape/2 files), 1985 June 1 (Box T2, Item 124)
      Labeled on 2 sides. [Per index, re: When Smart People Fail]